export default Dpe3 = [
    {
        question: "1. Light follows which law during refraction",
        options: ["Refractive index",
            "Total internal reflection",
            "Snell's law",
            "Fermat law"],
        correct_option: "Snell's law"
    },

    {
        question: "2. If critical angle is 450, then refractive index is",
        options: ["1.44",
            "1.0003",
            "1.33",
            "1.31"],
        correct_option: "1.33"
    },
    {
        question: "3. Mirages are",
        options: ["Real image",
            "Virtual image of sky",
            "Secretes of nature",
            "Virtual image"],
        correct_option: "Virtual image of sky"
    },
    {
        question: "4.  n_{1}  sin i= n_{2}  sin r is called",
        options: ["Huygens's law",
            "Fermat's law",
            "Newton's law",
            "Snell's law"],
        correct_option: "Snell's law"
    },

    {
        question: "6. Mirages are an example for",
        options: ["Total internal reflection",
            "Refraction",
            "Multiple reflection",
            "Critical angle"],
        correct_option: "Total internal reflection"
    },

    {
        question: "7. The refractive index value for Sapphire",
        options: ["1.71",
            "1.67",
            "1.77",
            "1.52"],
        correct_option: "1.77"
    },
    {
        question: "8. If speed of light were same in all the media,which of these processes are not possible",
        options: ["Dispersion",
            "Reflection",
            "Refraction & Dispersion",
            "Refraction"],
        correct_option: "Refraction & Dispersion"
    },

    {
        question: "9. When light travels from diamond to air,what happens?",
        options: ["Light bends towards normal",
            "Light doesn't bends towards normal",
            "Light bends away from the normal",
            "None"],
        correct_option: "Light bends away from the normal"
    },
    {
        question: "10. Optical fibres work on",
        options: ["Reflection",
            "Total internal reflection",
            "Refraction",
            "Multiple reflections"],
        correct_option: "Total internal reflection"
    },
    {
        question: "11. The brilliance of diamond is due to",
        options: ["Refraction",
            "Reflection",
            "Interference",
            "Total internal reflection"],
        correct_option: "Total internal reflection"
    },
    {
        question: "12. Refractive index value of ice > Refractive index of ruby\n" +
            "Is it true or not?any explanations.",
        options: ["Ice has no refractive index value",
            "False",
            "True",
            "None"],
        correct_option: "True"
    },


    {
        question: "14. The process of changing speed when light travels from one medium to another medium is called",
        options: ["Refraction of light",
            "Reflection of light",
            "Refractive index",
            "None"],
        correct_option: "Refraction of light"
    },
    {
        question: "15. Mirage is an",
        options: ["Optical disturbance",
            "Optical illusion",
            "Real image",
            "None"],
        correct_option: "Optical illusion"
    },

    {
        question: "16. In the following formula, 'n' represent n=c/v",
        options: ["Refractive index",
            "Reflection",
            "Refraction",
            "None"],
        correct_option: "Refractive index"
    },
    {
        question: "17. Suppose you are inside the water in a swimming pool,your friend is standing on the edge of swimming pool,your friend appears to be",
        options: ["Same size",
            "Shorter",
            "Taller",
            "Stout"],
        correct_option: "Taller"
    },
    {
        question: "18. A man photographed a white donkey after fitting black strips vertically on to the lens of his camera.what photo will he get?",
        options: ["A bright image of white donkey",
            "An image of zebra with vertical strips",
            "A dull image of white donkey",
            "An image of zebra with horizontal strips"],
        correct_option: "A dull image of white donkey"
    },
    {
        question: "19. Which of the following is the critical angle of diamond?",
        options: ["24.4",
            "24.4'",
            "24.4°",
            "None"],
        correct_option: "24.4°"
    },
    {
        question: "20. A test tube immersed at a certain angle in a tumbler of water to have a mirror surface for a certain viewing positon.it is due to",
        options: ["Reflection",
            "Scattering",
            "Refraction",
            "Total internal reflection"],
        correct_option: "Total internal reflection"
    },
]